Frank A. Stone Collection
© 2006 University of Connecticut
Frank A. Stone Collection.
undated,
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Stone, Frank A. [Collector].
4.8 linear feet.
MSS19970124
Biography
Scope and Content
Arrangement
Series I: Inventory ( )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. See also, The Peoples of Connecticut Prject Records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Stone, Frank.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut--Faculty.
Places:
Armenia--Study and teaching--Connecticut.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Oral Histories.; Audiovisual materials.
Occupations:
Educators.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Dr. Stone donated the materials in several installments beginning in 1997.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Inventory, undated
  - Various post cards from Europe, undated (Box 1)
  - Flyer--"The Soorp Badarak of the Armenian Apostolic Church" [22 copies], undated (Box 1)
  - Flyer--"Poland The Tatra Mountains", undated (Box 1)
  - My Name is Aram by William Saroyan, undated (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, Isaac N. Thut World Education Center, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Armenian Studies for Secondary Students by Frank A. Stone, 1975 (Box 1)
  - American Review, Spring-Winter, Volume 46 Number 1-4, 1993 (Box 1)
  - "Give Ararat Back to the Armenians", Bumper sticker, undated (Box 1)
  - Problems in Armenian Collection Development and Technical Processing in U.S. Libraries by Gia Aivazian, undated (Box 1)
  - The Genesis of the Armenian Question by Bilal N. Simsir, undated (Box 1)
  - Discovering History Through Artifacts Case Study: Kingdom of Tigran II "The Great", undated (Box 1)
  - Maps of Armenia, undated (Box 1)
  - Hairneik Daily, 1978 April 8 - 9 (Box 1)
  - "A Brief Introduction to Armenian History,", undated (Box 1)
  - Hoosharar, Vol. 62, No. 5, 7; Vo. 63, No. 1, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Why Armenians Commemorate This Day by Setrak Minas, undated (Box 1)
  - "Armenian Roots in Greater Hartford," (Sunday Magazine from Hartford Courant), 1977 December 18 (Box 1)
  - Armenian publications, undated, 1975, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Kir ou Kirk Letter and Literature An Armenian Periodical, Vol XVIII No 18-19, undated (Box 1)
  - Before and After by Leo Sarksian, 1915 (Box 1)
  - American Education Studies Association News and comment, undated (Box 1)
  - Armenian Studies, Alphabet, Rugs, Musical Instruments, undated (Box 1)
  - Project Save flyer, undated (Box 1)
  - Armenia and Armenians exhibit flyer, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Armenian Studies, Armenian Culture, History and Society, undated (Box 1)
  - Armenian Studies, Armenian Assembly of America Journal, undated (Box 1)
  - Armenian Studies, Armenian International Magazine, undated (Box 1)
  - Armenian Studies, Armenian Update magazine, undated (Box 1)
  - Armenian Studies, National Association for Armenian Studies and Research newsletter, undated (Box 1)
  - Armenian Studies, Society for Armenian Studies newsletter, undated (Box 1)
  - Oral History, Armenian Mrs. Yeghar Ataian Manoogian, undated (Box 1)
  - Rev. Mashtote Vartabed Papaziantz, An Armenian Priest, undated (Box 1)
  - Young People Caught Up in a Catastrophe: Experiences of Children and Youth Who Survived the Armenian Genocide of 1915 by Frank Stone, undated (Box 1)
  - Armenian Studies for Secondary Students, 1975, 1979 (Box 1)
  - The Puerto Ricans: On the Island, On the Mainland, In Connecticut, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Teaching and Being Taught in Turkey by Barbara M. and Frank A. Stone, undated (Box 1)
  - English Lit. 17th Century, undated (Box 1)
  - Course material for EDFC 220 "Foundations of Education,", undated (Box 1)
  - Armenian cigarettes, undated (Box 2)
  - Armenian desk flag, undated (Box 2)
  - Armenian arm band, undated (Box 2)
  - Armenian art pieces, undated (Box 2)
  - Copper bowl, undated (Box 2)
  - A Houseful of Love by Majorie Housepian, undated (Box 2)
  - Slide carousel with slides entitled "Armenian Art, Architecture, and Traditional Fold Crafts" (128 slides used with ESIM 302, undated (Box 2)
  - Slide carousel with 80 slides "They Came from Ararat: The Story of Armenian Americans" used with ESIM 302, undated (Box 2)
  - Button from the National Gathering of Survivors of the Armenian Genocide, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Slide tray with 21 slides used with ESIM 302, "The Armenian Sisters' Academy," Radnor, PA, undated (Box 2)
  - Slide tray with 29 slides used with ESIM 302, "American Missionary Education in the 19th Century-American Board Schools in the Ottoman Empire and Sandwich Islands,", undated (Box 2)
  - Slide tray with 35 slides, "Kevork Esyan Becomes an Armenian American,", undated (Box 2)
  - Slide tray with 36 slides used with ESIM 448-ME, "Armenian In the Caucasus and Middle East: Past and Present,", undated (Box 2)
  - Slide tray with 16 slides used with ESIM 302, "An Armenian Festival In New Britain, CT,", undated (Box 2)
  - Slide tray with 16 slides used with ESIM 448-ME, "Armenian Illustrated Manuscripts,", undated (Box 2)
  - Sony Video tape for Helical scan video recorders "An Armenian School in Connecticut, undated (Box 2)
  - Audio cassettes, undated (Box 2)
    - "They Came from Ararat: The Story of Armenian Americans"
    - "Interview with S. Dardouri of Sis (Kozan)"
    - "Oral History Interview tih Mr. Vahan Kahlian"
    - "Armenian Education Through the Ages Prof. Kevork Kherlopian"
    - "Sister Arousiag discusses Ervian Conference of Armenian Teachers"
    - "Excerpts of the Armenian Divine Liturgy at St. Stephen's Church"
    - Interview with Mrs. Eliza Sachaklian"
    - "Oral history with Kevork Esayan"
    - "Mrs. Hripsime Kaprealian"
    - "Mrs. Hripsime Kaprealian's Story of Her deportation and rescue 1915"
  - USSR No 11 (26), undated (Box 3)
  - Ms of The Heritage of Armenia or Euphrates College by Frank Stone, undated (Box 3)
  - Armenian pubications, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - 2 clippings of picture (probably in Armenia) posted on construction paper, undated (Box 3)
  - Poster--of an Armenian Coat of Arms, undated (Box 3)
  - Maps of Armenia at different times, undated (Box 3)
  - Poster--The Evolution of the Armenian Alphabet, undated (Box 3)
  - Medieval Armenian costumes, undated (Box 3)
  - Poster--Symbolical Picture of Armenia, undated (Box 3)
  - Poster--Hayric Huefry [?], undated (Box 3)